euroncap.com 2019-06-17

# Euro NCAP | Privacy Statement

We understand that your trust in us, is European New Car Assessment Programme ivzw / aisbl’s most important asset (hereinafter referred to as "Euro NCAP", "we" or "us").  As such, your privacy is essential for us.

This privacy statement (hereinafter referred to as "Privacy Statement") is applicable, inter alia, to **(i)** our website [www.euroncap.com](https://www.euroncap.com/) (hereinafter referred to as the "Website") and **(ii)** all (commercial) relations between Euro NCAP and its customers, prospects and business partners.

This Privacy Statement includes information about the personal data collected by Euro NCAP, as well as the manner in which Euro NCAP uses and processes this personal data.

Euro NCAP wishes to emphasize that it always attempts to act in accordance with **(i)** the Belgian Privacy Law of 8 December 1992 on privacy protection in relation to the processing of personal data and/or **(ii)** the EU Regulation of 2016 concerning the protection of individuals with regards to the processing of personal data, regarding the free movement of such data and repealing Directive 95/46/EC and **(iii)** all (future) Belgian laws regarding the implementation of this Regulation.

Visiting the Website, appealing on the services of Euro NCAP, the purchase of products/goods of, any and every (form of) communication with Euro NCAP and/or subscription to an event/webinar/seminar implies your explicit approval (through disclosure of your personal information or opt-in) of the Privacy Statement and consequently how we collect, use and process your personal data.

Please read this Privacy Statement in conjunction with Euro NCAP’s legal disclaimer cookie policy.

## Types of personal data

Euro NCAP can collect and process the following personal data:

### Registration to the Euro NCAP’s latest news

  * E-mail address

### Submitting the website contact form

  * Name
  * Surname
  * E-mail address
  * All personal data provided in the ‘free field’ when completing the contact form on the website

### Registration to events/webinars/seminars

  * Name
  * Surname
  * E-mail address
  * Telephone number (landline and/or mobile phone)
  * Residence address
  * Customer number
  * Passport number
  * Sex
  * Date of birth
  * Fax
  * Company name
  * Company address
  * Invoicing address

### Use of the website

  * IP-address

### General

  * All personal data provided in the ‘free field’ when completing the contact form on the website
  * All personal data freely provided to Euro NCAP (e.g. in light of correspondence with Euro NCAP).

Euro NCAP also automatically collects anonymous information regarding your use of the Website. As such, shall, for example, automatically log which sections of the Website and Platform you visit, which web browser you use, which website you visited when you obtained access to the Website.  We cannot identify you through these data, but it allows Euro NCAP to draw up statistics regarding the use of the Website.

## Methods of personal data collection:

These personal data are collected in the context of:

  * Visiting the Website
  * Collaboration with Euro NCAP
  * Incoming and outgoing correspondence with Euro NCAP
  * Requesting an offer of Euro NCAP
  * Subscription to the Euro NCAP’s latest news (whether or not through the website)
  * Appealing on the services of Euro NCAP, (whether or not through the website)
  * Subscription to a webinar/seminar/event of Euro NCAP
  * Exchanging business cards.

All personal data, collected by Euro NCAP, are thus expressly and voluntarily provided by you.

Providing certain personal data is (sometimes) a requirement to be able to enjoy certain services (e.g. to gain access to certain parts of the Website, to subscribe to Euro NCAP’s latest news, to participate in certain activities and events).  In this respect, it shall be indicated which data must be provided mandatory and which data is optional.

## Use of personal data

Euro NCAP can use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * Performance of the agreement with Euro NCAP (incl. follow-up thereof)
  * Responding to questions (whether or not received through the contact form)
  * Sending Euro NCAP’s latest news
  * Creating statistics
  * Drawing up a quote
  * Follow-up after a meeting
  * Confirmation of the subscription to a webinar/seminar or event of Euro NCAP
  * Issuing invoices and the collection thereof.

Processing takes place on the following legal grounds, as the case may be:

  * You have given consent to the processing of your personal data for one or more specific purposes
  * Processing is necessary for the performance of the agreement with Euro NCAP or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into an agreement
  * Processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which Euro NCAP is subject
  * Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by Euro NCAP or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject, which require protection of personal data (in particular when you are a child).

## Disclosure of personal data to third parties

Euro NCAP shall not disclose your personal data to third parties, unless it is necessary in the context of performing the agreement and optimisation thereof (including but not limited to maintenance works and for the delivery of services to Euro NCAP).  In this respect, your personal data may be disclosed to payment providers, software providers, cloud partner, external IT-consultants, financial institutions, insurance companies and/or (external) service providers.

If it is necessary that Euro NCAP discloses your personal data to third parties, the third party concerned is required to use your personal data in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Statement.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, it is however possible that Euro NCAP discloses your personal data:

  * To the competent authorities (i) if Euro NCAP is obliged to do so under the law or under legal or future legal proceedings and (ii) to safeguard and defend our rights
  * If Euro NCAP, or the majority of its assets, are taken over by a third party, in which case your personal data – which Euro NCAP has collected – shall be one of the transferred assets.

In all other cases, Euro NCAP will not sell, hire out or pass on your personal data to third parties, except when it **(i)** has obtained your permission to this end and **(ii)** has completed a data processing agreement with the third party in question, which contains the necessary guarantees regarding confidentiality and privacy compliance of your personal data.

## Cross-border processing of personal data

Any transfer of personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA) to a recipient whose domicile or registered office is in a country which does not fall under the adequacy decision enacted by the European Commission, shall be governed by the provisions of a data transfer agreement, which shall contain **(i)** the standard contractual clauses, as referred to in the 'European Commission decision of 5 February 2010 (Decision 2010/87/EC)', or **(ii)** any other mechanism pursuant to privacy legislation, or any other regulations pertaining to the processing of personal data.

## Storage of personal data 

Unless a longer storage period is required or justified **(i)** by law or **(ii)** through compliance with another legal obligation, Euro NCAP shall only store your personal data for the period necessary to achieve and fulfil the purpose in question, as specified in the Privacy Statement under 'Use of personal data'.

## Your privacy rights

In light of the processing of your personal data, you enjoy the following privacy rights:

  * Right of access to your personal data
  * Right to rectification, completion or update of your personal data
  * Right to delete your personal data ('right to be forgotten').
  * Right to limit the processing of your personal data
  * Right to transferability of your personal data
  * Right to object, to oppose the processing of your personal data.

If you wish to invoke your privacy rights please contact privacy@euroncap.com.

If you no longer wish to receive Euro NCAP’s latest news or information about the services of Euro NCAP, you can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" button underneath each of Euro NCAP’s mailings.

## Security of personal data

Euro NCAP undertakes to take reasonable, physical, technological and organisational precautions in order to avoid **(i)** unauthorised access to your personal information, and **(ii)** loss, abuse or alteration of your personal data.

Euro NCAP shall store all personal data, which it has collected, in the cloud with data centres in the EU.

Notwithstanding Euro NCAP’s security policy, the checks it carries out and the actions it proposes in this context, an infallible level of security cannot be guaranteed.  Since no method of transmission or forwarding over the internet, or any method of electronic storage is 100% secure, Euro NCAP is, in this context, not in a position to guarantee absolute security.

## Update Privacy Statement

Euro NCAP is entitled to update this Privacy Statement by posting a new version on the Website.  As such, it is strongly recommended to regularly consult the Website and the page displaying the Privacy Statement, to make sure that you are aware of any changes.

## Other websites

The Website may potentially contain hyperlinks to other websites.  When you click on one of these links, you may be redirected to another website or internet source that could collect information about you through cookies or other technologies.  Euro NCAP does not bear any responsibility, liability or control authority over these other websites or internet resources, nor about their collection, use and disclosure of your personal data.  You must check the privacy statements of these other websites and internet sources in order to be able to judge whether they act in accordance with the Privacy Legislation.

## Contact Euro NCAP

If you have questions and/or remarks about this Privacy Statement or the manner in which Euro NCAP collects, uses and/or processes your personal data, please contact us:

  * Via e-mail: [privacy@euroncap.com](mailto:privacy@euroncap.com)
  * or
  * Via post: Euro NCAP – Mgr Ladeuzeplein 10 – B-3000 Leuven – Belgium

In case you are not satisfied with the way Euro NCAP handled your questions and/or remarks or you have any complaints about the way Euro NCAP collects, uses and and/or processes your personal data, note that you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Privacy Commission.

  **June 2018**
